# **Matthew Lyon**

Manchester, United Kingdom 

I am currently a PhD student in the Machine Learning group at the University of Manchester. My research focuses on improving MRI data through deep learning, and incorporating geometric priors into deep learning models. I have prior experience working as a research software engineer at several research institutes.

### Education

2020 - 2024 **PhD in Computer Science,** *University of Manchester* 

**United Kingdom** 

2015 - 2016 **Master of Medical Physics,** *University of Sydney* 

Australia

2011 - 2014 **BSc (Hons) in Physics,** *University of Warwick* 

**United Kingdom** 

# Professional Experience

08/2019 - 08/2020 **Research Software Engineer,** Save Sight Institute

Sydney, Australia Part Time 0.8 FTE

• Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.

• Lead algorithm design and optimisation workflows.

Consulted on neuroimaging analysis techniques and signal processing.

08/2019 - 01/2020

**Neuroimaging Analyst,** Sydney Neuroimaging Research Centre

Sydney, Australia Part Time 0.4 FTE

• Developed and implemented neuroimaging analysis pipelines.

Performed QC on MRI analysis.

07/2017 - 07/2019

**Research Software Engineer,** Heart Research Institute

Sydney, Australia Full Time

• Built and managed a distributed computing cluster.

• Developed, tested, and documented neuroimaging processing pipelines.

• Oversaw data ingestion and QC/QA, created dashboard visualisations.

• Conducted clinical research using MRI data.

## Technologies

Python • TensorFlow • Keras • PyTorch • NumPy • C++ • Ubuntu • Docker • Bash • Matlab

#### Publications

2022 Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional

**Autoencoder, MIDL 2022** 

Matthew Lyon, Paul Armitage, Mauricio A. Álvarez

2019	Gender-specific structural abnormalities in major depressive disorder revealed by fixel-based analysis, NeuroImage: Clinical Matthew Lyon, Thomas Welton, Adrina Varda, Jerome J. Maller, Kathryn Broadhouse, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, Evian Gordon, A. John Rush, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Is occipital bending a structural biomarker of risk for depression and sensitivity to treatment?, Journal of Clinical Neuroscience Karen Fullard, Jerome J. Maller, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Evian Gordon, Stephen H. Koslow, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Profound and reproducible patterns of reduced regional gray matter characterize major depressive disorder, <i>Translational Psychiatry</i> Sarah C. Hellewell, Thomas Welton, Jerome J. Maller, Matthew Lyon, Mayuresh S. Korgaonkar, Stephen H. Koslow, Leanne M. Williams, John A. Rush, Evian Gordon, Stuart M. Grieve
2019	Structural core of the executive control network: A high angular resolution diffusion MRI study, Human Brain Mapping Kai-kai Shen, Thomas Welton, Matthew Lyon, Andrew N. McCorkindale, Greg T. Sutherland, Samantha Burnham, Jurgen Fripp, Ralph Martins, Stuart M. Grieve
Talks	
Zurich, Switzerland	Medical Imaging with Deep Learning, MIDL 2022 ☑ Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional Autoencoder
Manchester, United Kingdom	Advances in Data Science and Al Conference, ASDAI 2022  Angular Super-Resolution in Diffusion MRI with a 3D Recurrent Convolutional Autoencoder
invited Reviewer	
Valencia, Spain	International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics, AISTATS 2022
New Orleans, USA	Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems, NeurIPS 2022
<b>I</b> Courses	
10/2020	C++: From Beginner to Expert, Udemy
06/2020	Convolutional Neural Networks, Coursera
06/2020	Sequence Models, Coursera
02/2020	Neural Networks and Deep Learning, Coursera

**Machine Learning,** Coursera

01/2020